每年在下雪前
Every year before the snow came,
我爸爸都会烧残骸
my father would burn slash piles--
动物尸体  落下的树枝
mounds of dead, fallen brush,
火焰有谷仓那么高
with flames as high as the barn.
我会抬起头  顶着高温
I'd hold my face up to the heat
逼自己靠近
and dare myself closer
就像我是在朝着太阳走一样
like I was walking into the sun.
呸
Boo.
-水和泥土  -你分析了吗
- Water and dirt. - You analyzed it?
海德伍德夫妇分析了  什么都没发现
The Headwoods did. It's nothing.
毫无意外  所以你为什么取样这个
It's exactly what you'd expect, so why did you sample this?
里面有硫酸铵吗
Was there ammonium sulfate in it?
嗯  多半是火山岩
Mm-hmm, it's probably volcanic.
那又如何
So what?
他警告过我这个  他说你会有所保留
He warned me about this. He said that you hold back.
这是你的主要战术
It's your main move.
他说世界上有两种人
He said that there is two different types of people in this world.
一种是梦想家一种是阴谋家
There's dreamers and there's schemers,
梦想家可以打造世界
and the dreamers can build the world up,
而阴谋家会趁机溜过
but the schemers slither their way through.
你是怎么想的
What do you think?
我认为他嗨了后话很多
I think that he says a lot when he's high.
当时外面在下雪
It was snowing outside.
-天空上下下来的吗  -没错
- From the sky? - From the sky.
不可能
Mm-hmm, that's impossible.
-本应不可能  但我看到了  -我们不会看到雪
- It should be, but I saw it. - We don't get snow.
太冷了
It's too cold.
我们只有高吹雪和以前的沉淀
We get blowing snow and old precip.
你或许能影响到他
You might get into his head,
但你影响不了我
but you're not getting into mine.
熄灯
Lights out.
当艾莉克斯年龄足够大时
When Alex was old enough,
她帮我用水管冲洗灰池
she helped me hose down the ash pits,
我会像我爸警告我那样警告她
and I'd warn her like my dad warned me
里面潜伏的高温
of the heat lurking inside,
准备像鬼魂来访一样闷烧起来
ready to smolder to life like a visit from a ghost.
现在是她在雪国列车上的循环
These are her revolutions now on Snowpiercer,
1034节车厢
1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第二集
"暖意渐生"
早上好
Good morning.
今天就别去三等厢了
Hey, maybe stay out of Third today?
我得去帮助佩尔顿医生
I gotta help Dr. Pelton today.
我不会有事的
I'll be fine.
听着  马泰奥还在生你气  扎拉
Look, Mateo is still angry with you, Zarah.
给下面你的人一点时间冷静
Give it some time to cool off down there?
让佩尔顿去二等厢诊所工作
Ask Pelton to work in the Second Class clinic.
好
Okay.
别担心  我不会有事
Don't worry. I'll be safe.
我在想
I was thinking--
这孩子需要名字  对吧
this kid's gonna need a name, right?
那还用说
Pretty sure that's how it works.
如果是女孩
Well, if it's a girl,
你觉得用你妈妈的名字命名怎么样
how would you feel about naming it after your mom?
如果是男孩呢
And if it's a boy?
托洛茨基
Trotsky.
晚点再谈吧
We'll talk about this later.
稍等
Hey, one second.
早
Morning.
真高兴你们安顿下来了
Nice to see you two landed on your feet.
这是给扎拉和孩子的
It's for Zarah and the baby.
嗯  有一个能称为家的地方很好
Yeah, no, no, it's good to have a place to call home.
安德烈
Hey, Andre...
我很为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
别尬
Don't be weird.
快来
Come on.
列车上的人状态怎么样
How's the train holding together?
比我好
Better than me.
车上一半的人认为威尔福德是来杀我们的
Half the train thinks Wilford's here to kill us.
另一半认为他是来从你手中解救我们的
The other half think he's here to save us from you.
他们也许是对的
They might all be right.
总人口增加了四百车尾人
And adding 400 Tailies to the population hasn't exactly
并没有降低温度
lowered the temperature.
昨晚在茶室附近发生了一起袭击
There was an assault near the Tea Room last night.
-一名车尾女人受伤致残  -谁
- A Tailie woman got maimed. - Who?
我不知道
I don't know.
你能去查清原委吗
Can you find out what happened?
我  凭什么
Me? On what authority?
我不再是司闸员了  莱顿
I'm not a Brakeman anymore, Layton.
我现在只是...  你的跟班
I just... I just follow you around.
好吧  我们解决这问题  跟我来
All right, let's fix that. Come on.
-什么  -快来
- What? - Come on.
罗切  起来  我们来完成这事
Roche, stand up. Let's do this.
-现在吗  -对
- What, now? - Yeah.
贝丝·提尔  请举起右手
Bess Till please raise your right hand.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
贝丝·提尔  我在此任命你为列车警探
Bess Till, I hereby pronounce you train detective.
不不不  我没主动要求这个
No, no, no, no, I didn't ask for this.
谁会想主动收拾现在这烂摊子呢
Imagine anyone asking for any of this.
听我说  我没准备好
Listen to me, I'm not ready.
他直接给你升职了
He's straight up giving you a promotion.
但我不想
Well, I don't want it!
我已经见过够多流血和杀戮了
I've seen enough blood for a while.
我们都惊魂未定  但现在由我们管事
We're all shaky, but we are in charge now,
我们对其余乘客有责任
and we have a responsibility to the rest of the passengers.
好吧  你想要我做什么
All right. What do you want me to do?
我们得在这里审问一名战俘
Well, we have to interrogate a POW in here,
如果你能去查袭击的事
so if you could get on top of this assault thing,
-我会很感激  -警探
- I would really appreciate it. - Detective.
恭喜  刚才的仪式很动人
Congratulations, that was a really beautiful ceremony.
女士们先生们  贝丝·提尔警探
Ladies and gentlemen, Detective Bess Till.
凯文·麦克曼  出生地纽约水牛城
Kevin McMann, born in Buffalo, New York,
以乘客服务部学徒身份登上雪国列车
ticketed on Snowpiercer as a hospitality apprentice.
-现在我是部门主管  -恭喜啊
- I'm head of department now. - Ah, cheers.
你们列车上有多少人
So how many people you looking after back there?
我拒绝回答  谢谢
I'm gonna decline to answer, thanks.
你们看起来有点饿
You guys looked a little hungry.
你们的食物系统还撑得住吗
How your food systems holding up?
不回答
Pass.
听着  你不用怕威尔福德
Look, you don't have to fear Wilford.
-你在这里很安全  -怕他
- You're safe up here. - Fear him?
我崇拜那个男人
I adore the man.
我记得你  你以前是安保  对吧
I remember you. Security, right?
戴着耳机走来走去
Walked around with your little earpiece,
在他进入房间前先确认安全
cleared the room before he entered
有点像门卫
kind of like a doorman.
是有点
Kind of.
安保  工程部  农业部
Security, engineering, agriculture--
都只是管道系统  但乘客服务部
it's all just plumbing, but Hospitality--
乘客服务部从心出发
Hospitality comes from the heart.
是一种文化  一种爱
It's a culture. It's a kind of love.
他会来救我的
He'll come for me.
我要说的就这些
That's all I'm gonna say.
-这是真的吗  -真鸡肉  对
- Is that real? - Real chicken, yeah.
真醋  真辣椒
It's real vinegar, real cayenne.
跟家乡一样的水牛城风味
That's Buffalo style just like home.
吃吧
Dig in.
跟我们说说那个
Tell us about the big guy
脸像棒球手套一样厚的大块头
with a baseball mitt for a face.
他为什么不受极寒影响
Why wasn't he affected by the cold?
好了
Okay.
他被增强了耐寒性
He was augmented for cold resistance.
怎么做到的
How?
我不知道
I don't know.
移植法或人造皮肤之类的
Grafting or synthetic skin stuff.
-我不是科学家  -好吧
- I-I'm not a scientist. - Okay.
大爱丽丝上有多少工作人员
Uh-uh--how many crew aboard Big Alice?
大概猜个数  10个  20个
Estimate, guess. 10, 20?
50个
50?
一百个
100.
坐下  他很快就出来
Have a seat. He'll be out shortly.
不用  不过谢了
No, no. Thanks, though.
早上好
Morning.
大家睡得好吗
How'd everyone sleep?
不好吗
Not good?
团聚有时会有些棘手
Well, reunions can be a little tricky.
艾莉克斯  跟我说说
Alex, tell me about
你在外面的小研究项目
your little research project outside.
听起来似乎没用
Bit of a dud, by the sounds of it.
对  看样子是的
Yeah, yeah, looks that way.
艾莉克斯  你妈妈的特别之处在于
The thing about your mother, Alex,
她是个修补匠
is she's a tinkerer.
捣鼓卡钳还行  但是
Decent with a set of calipers, but...
别指望她有多少远见
don't expect much vision.
我知道你认为你让我们陷入了僵局
I know you think you've stalemated us,
但我们还有招  对吧  艾莉克斯
but we still have moves. Don't we, Alex?
我们可以踩刹车  减速缓行
We can apply the brakes, slow it to a crawl,
切断你们的动力  使你们的系统关闭
choke out your power, and shut down your systems.
你们的也会
And yours.
我的人知道如何在零度以下生活
My crew know life below zero.
我们一同经历过很多崎岖的路程
We've run a lot of rough miles together.
雪国列车会分崩离析
Snowpiercer will tear herself apart.
当灯熄灭
It's a hell of a test for a leader
食物供应不上时  这对领导者就是巨大的考验
when the lights go out and the food stops flowing.
你觉得那位莱顿先生能撑多久
How long do you think this Mr. Layton will last?
他可能会让你刮目相看
I think he might surprise you.
那我还真得会会他
I guess I'd better meet him then.
有动静
Movement.
蹲下  蹲下
Get down, get down.
等等  别碰它
Wait, don't touch it.
可能有毒  对吗
I mean, it could be poison, right?
叫乘客服务部的人来
Get Hospitality.
乘客服务部  让下路
Hospitality, make way!
怎么了  怎么了
What's going on, what's going on?
一群傻子  这是公报
Fools, it's a communiqué.
公报  让路
Communiqué, clear the way.
让让
Make way.
公报来了
Communiqué coming through.
威尔福德亲手写的
It's in Wilford's own hand.
-露丝  露丝  -简直无可挑剔
- Ruth. Ruth. - It's impeccable.
好的
All right.
威尔福德先生说我们一开始闹得不太愉快
Mr. Wilford suggests that we got off on the wrong foot,
他想见你  莱顿先生
and he would like to meet you, Mr. Layton.
他建议在正式囚犯交换时见面
He suggests that that happens at a formal prisoner swap,
梅兰妮换凯文
Melanie for Kevin.
好  我们必须这么做
Okay, we have to make that happen.
他可能会一枪崩了你的头
Yeah, might put a bullet in your head.
胡说  罗切
That's nonsense, Roche.
别带着恶意揣测他人
Let's not assume bad faith.
如果我们困在了一起
If we're stuck together,
我们必须开始相互交流
we're gonna have to start talking.
没错  我现在得和他同步
Yes, I have to run two engines
运行两个火车头
in sync with him now.
好吧  但他怎么会交出梅兰妮
Yeah, but why would he hand over Melanie?
他在耍什么花招
What's the play?
不像某些人  威尔福德先生很重视乘客服务部
Mr. Wilford, unlike some, values hospitality.
尽管笑话我吧  罗切先生
Laugh at me all you like, Mr. Roche,
我可以肯定  凯文这个筹码比你们想得更重要
I'm telling you that Kevin is a bigger chip than you realize.
那好吧  如果这是公平交换
Okay, well, if it's an even exchange,
那他就是想看着我们
then what he really wants is to look at us.
那我们也看着他
So we'll watch him too.
我们知道他们大概有100个人
We know that they number about 100
而且都很饥饿  这是我们的优势
and that they're hungry. That's good leverage.
好  去接梅兰妮回家吧
All right, let's bring Melanie home.
告诉他们协议成交
Tell 'em we have a deal.
见到你很高兴  罗切  安妮还好吗
Nice to see you, Roche. How's Anne?
-她很好  先生  -那就好
- She's great, sir. - Oh, good.
那是...那是露丝·沃德尔吗
And is that-- is that Ruth Wardell?
你换发型了吗  露丝
Have you changed your hair, Ruth?
是的  先生
Yes, sir, I have,
我想代表大家说一句
and might I say on behalf of everyone
能再次见到您  我们不胜感激
how truly grateful we are to see you again.
好了  办正事吧
Okay, let's get this done.
想必这就是莱顿大王本人吧
Oh, and here he is in the flesh--King Layton.
不  先生
No, sir.
这里没有王权
No kings here.
现在的雪国列车属于人民
Snowpiercer belongs to the people now.
是吗
Oh, does she?
那能麻烦你们的人民
Well, then, could you please ask the people
交出我的服务部部长吗
to produce my head of Hospitality?
先立好规矩
Rules first.
只有囚犯才能穿过无人区
No one crosses the no man's land but the prisoners.
任何突然的行为都会被视作挑衅
Any sudden moves will be taken as a sign of aggression.
同意
Agreed.
带他过来
Bring him.
我很好  威尔福德先生  我没事
I'm fine, Mr. Wilford. I'm okay.
凯文
Hi, Kevin.
-我走之前想见艾莉克斯  -下次吧  梅兰妮
- I wanna see Alex before I go. - Next time, Melanie.
我们会来找你的
We'll come to you.
好了  莱顿大王  就等你的准许了
All right, King Layton, with your permission.
等等
Wait!
开枪  开枪
Take the shot! Take the shot!
-不要  住手  -别开枪
- No, stop! - Hold your fire.
住手
Stop!
你忘了这个
You forgot this.
快告诉我这是什么
Just tell me what it is.
我暂时不知道
I don't know yet.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
我们可以一起研究
We'll study it together.
不
No.
你来晚了七年
You're seven years too late.
你的火车怎么样了  莱顿
How's your train, Layton?
乘客有崩溃迹象
Passengers are starting to show cracks.
过往的分歧根深蒂固
Old divides run deep.
大爱丽丝呢  威尔福德的下一步是什么
What about Big Alice? What's Wilford's next move?
他自己都不知道
I don't think he knows yet.
他花了好几年筹划这次进攻
He planned this attack for years.
-现在只能即兴而为  -他为什么会交出你
- Now he's improvising. - Why he turned you over?
-好研究我们这边吗  -是研究你
- To study our side? - To study you.
他要冲你来了  莱顿  别搞错了
He's coming for you, Layton. Make no mistake.
你女儿还好吗
Your daughter okay?
她很无情
She's cruel.
困惑不已  她还恨我
She's confused, and she hates me.
青少年都这样
So she's a teenager.
你在外面待了很久  去看看医生吧
You were out there a long time. We should get you to a doctor.
不了  去火车头
No, to the Engine.
我得去找本和哈维谈话
I need to talk to Ben and Javi.
借过
Excuse me.
他说了什么
What did he say?
听着  我得见昨晚被袭击的女人
Look, I need to see the woman who was assaulted last night.
是吗  但她不想见司闸员
Yeah, well, she don't wanna see no Brakeman.
那幸好莱顿让我做了列车警探了
Yeah, well, it's a good thing Layton made me train detective then.
后退
Hey, back it up, yo!
-后退  -放开  别碰我
- Back up! - Get off! Hands off!
她和你们一同并肩作战  打什么打
She fought alongside you for Christ's sake.
离开我的走廊
Now get out of my doorway.
-快走  -谢谢
- Get! - Thanks.
无论如何
Whatever it's worth.
我不确定你是否能有更多进展
I don't know if you're gonna get much further.
莱茨
Lights.
贝丝
Bess.
-你能告诉我发生了什么吗  -他们砍断了她的手指
- Can you tell me what happened? - They cut off her fingers.
谁
Who?
我没看见脸
I--I didn't see faces.
他们用袋子罩住了我的头  然后一拥而上
They put a bag over my head and piled on.
她之前在茶室
She was up by the Tea Room.
你知道他们用了什么武器吗
Do you know what weapon they used on your fingers?
-可能是斧头  -天呐  这鬼地方
- Axe maybe. - Jesus Christ, this place.
-我能走了吗  -这是给车尾的信息
- Can I go? - It's a message to the Tail.
他们袭击手  让她以后无法工作
They went at the hands so she can't work.
我只想回到列车后方
I just want back downtrain.
前方容不下我们
There's no place for us up there.
听着  我是想帮你  莱茨
Look, I'm trying to help you, Lights.
为时已晚
It's too late.
我取样了一点雪  结果发现
I took a sample of the snow, and it turns out
-里面含有硫酸铵  -你怎么知道的
- there's ammonium sulfate in it. - How do you know?
你还记得海德伍德夫妇吗
Do you remember the Headwoods?
他们活下来了
Well, they survived.
他们在那建立了一个生物实验室
They have a whole wet lab over there.
他们在研究组织重生
They're studying tissue regeneration.
对了  这个伤口在他们最初治疗时
That, by the way, was third-degree frostbite
是三级冻伤
when they first treated it.
现在几乎完全愈合了
It's almost completely healed.
等等  硫酸铵
Back up-- ammonium sulfate
在雪里
in the snow?
火山岩吗
Volcanic?
我想是CW7
I think it was CW7.
我觉得它在大气中变性
I think it denatured in the atmosphere,
-现在飘下来了  -为什么
- and now it's coming down. - Why?
-你为什么会这么想  -因为下雪了  哈维
- Why would you think that? - 'Cause it was snowing, Javi.
外面有情况
Something's happening out there.
有东西在变化
Something's changing.
如果CW7飘下来了  如果的话
If the CW7's falling--if--
我们需要知道有多久了  得搞清楚飘下来的速率
we need to know for how long. We need to find out the rate.
得搞清楚海拔
We need to find out the altitude.
我很高兴你回来了
I'm glad you're back aboard.
我们行动吧
Let's get on this, huh?
-大家需要听到一些好消息  -好的  老大
- Train could use some good news. - Yes, boss.
我来给您汇报  先生
Here to give my report, sir.
你来了
Here he is.
进来  进来
Come in, come in.
-你让我好生担心  小伙子  -我知道
- You had me worried, son. - I know.
我很抱歉  但是  请放心
I'm very sorry, but, rest assured,
他们对我挺好的
they treated me fine.
那就好  那就好
Good, good.
你希望水多热
How hot do you want the water?
给我的吗
For me?
你肯定累坏了  你值得好好泡个澡
You must be exhausted. You've earned a good soak.
您真慷慨  但是
Oh, that's very generous, but--
凯文  别推拖了
Kevin, let me do this for you.
来吧
Come on.
你可以一边搓澡一边告诉我
You can scrub while you tell me
你在那的所见所闻
all about what you saw up there.
这个嘛
Well...
他们的机械运转似乎一切正常
they seem to be rolling fine mechanically,
但社会方面一团乱
but socially they're in shambles.
忽视规章制度  漠视命令
Protocol is ignored, orders open.
他们似乎已经没有阶级了
Don't think they even have classes anymore.
那莱顿呢
And Layton?
我觉得他就是随机应变吧
Winging it, as far as I can tell.
他不让乘客服务部参与关键决策
He keeps Hospitality out of key decisions.
我亲眼看到的
I saw that with my own eyes.
人们都不知道自己的归属了
People don't know where they belong,
不知如何生存
how to be.
我们在交界处看到了
We saw at the border.
没有指挥链  大家都疑心重重
No chain of command, everyone second-guessing.
没错
Exactly.
混乱不堪
Totally untangled.
那你透露了我们的什么信息
And what did you reveal about us?
什么也没说
Oh, nothing.
只说了一切正常
Only that all is well.
他们给你吃东西了吗
Did they feed you?
没有
No.
他们给了我鸡肉
No, they offered me chicken,
但是  所以我吃了几口
but...so, yes, I had a few bites,
但那是午餐时间
but, uh, you know, it was lunchtime,
感觉应该吃一点
so it seemed appropriate.
你先出去  艾莉克斯
I need the room, Alex.
我可以出去
Oh, I can get out.
不不  留下
Oh, no, no, no. Stay, stay.
你让他们知道了我们在挨饿  凯文
You showed 'em we were hungry, Kevin.
那是个秘密  是我们的弱点
That's a secret. It's a vulnerability.
先生  那...
Sir, it was...
只是  只是吃了点鸡翅
it was just-- it was a few wings.
那芒果呢
What about the mangoes
你在边境那拿的
you got at the border, hm?
我以为那可以鼓舞士气
I thought it would boost morale.
你为他们打开了大门
You opened the door for them.
你让他们进到我的房子里
You let them into my house,
所以  我们走到这步
so here we are.
我觉得我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
我很荣幸  孩子  很荣幸
It's been an honor, son, an honor.
你把任务完成得很好
You served the mission well.
谁来管理乘客服务部
Who will run Hospitality?
你现在不用在乎那些事了  凯文
You're free of that now, Kevin,
所有麻烦都不用管了
all your troubles.
你现在很暖和  你也自由了
You're warm, and you're free.
佩尔顿医生让我把这些带给你们
Dr. Pelton asked me to bring you these.
谢谢  你能把它们放到恢复室吗
Thanks, can you put them in the recovery room?
好
Sure.
乔茜
Josie.
这是个无名氏
You met our Jane Doe.
几个守卫把她带来的
A couple of Jackboots brought her in
就在战斗开始之前  严重冻伤
just before the fighting started. Severe frostbite.
她醒来过吗
She hasn't woken up yet?
没  可能不会醒来了  她现在情况很糟
No, she may not. She's in terrible shape.
基本上全身都很糟
Her whole body basically.
-你认识她吗  -不认识
- Do you know her? - No.
对不起  乔茜
I'm sorry, Josie.
不
Oh, no.
别  别  别
No, no, no, no, no.
借过
Excuse me.
茶室
罗根牧师
Ah, Pastor Logan?
我是贝丝·提尔  新任列车警探
I'm Bess Till. I'm the new train detective.
我猜你是关为过道的袭击事件而来
I guess this is about the assault down the corridor.
是的  也许你的访客中
Yeah, I was hoping one of your visitors
-会有人看到了什么  -我总是会倾听
- might have seen something. - Well, I always listen.
我会帮你打听打听  现在是异常时期
I'll ask around for you. These are strange times.
那个可怜的女人
That poor woman.
车尾人们经历了太多苦难
The Tailies have been through so much.
你应该和其他人一样清楚这点
Well, you would know that as well as anyone.
你曾是一个司闸员  对吗
You were a Brakeman, right?
你信奉哪一种信仰  罗根牧师
Uh, which team are you on, Pastor Logan?
这个  摩拉维亚圣经  1716年版
Ah, here, Moravian Bible, 1716,
德文原版
in the original German.
所以你是福音派信徒
Makes you an evangelical.
你对这挺了解的
You know your stuff.
我爸爸
My dad was--
信奉基督
Jesus-y.
那这个茶杯呢
And the teacup?
不论你信仰什么
Whatever faith you stand at,
你会从不同的角度看到这个茶杯
you see our cup from a different angle.
同一个茶杯  有裂纹且睿智  作为一个提醒
Same cup, cracked and wise. Just a reminder.
提醒我们全在注视着同一个神
We all contemplate one God?
换句话说
Put another way--
我们所有人都挤在这里
we're all crammed in here together,
-所以我们最好和睦相处  -你是这样吗
- so we better get along. - And, um, do you?
大多数日子是
Most days.
正如你所说的  现在是异常时期
These are strange times, like you say,
你觉得列车现在的氛围如何
how's the train feeling to you?
我是说  威尔福德本来死了  现在又复活了
I mean, Wilford was dead, and now he's resurrected.
这是个很有冲击力的故事
It's a powerful narrative.
有些人会为了适应当下
Some people will bend their faith
改变信仰
to fit the moment.
你是指威尔福德的信徒
You mean Wilford believers.
你说的四盎司
You said four ounces.
-这缺斤少两了  -是质量控制样品
- You're light. - Quality control sample.
它顺利通过搜查  朋友
It passed, my friend, with flying colors.
我可以多收点
I take more.
从补给最近在地缘政治上暂时中断了
Well, supply has been temporarily interrupted, geopolitically.
莱顿的搜查封锁了边境
Layton's raid locked down the border.
这是你的报酬
Your payment.
谁能想到大麻和《大英百科全书》
Who would've thought that weed and "Encyclopedia Britannicas"
变成像金子一样
would become gold?
老大  你有几个访客
Boss, got some visitors.
多么漂亮的一对
What a handsome couple.
我们想重新加入  特伦斯
We want back in, Terence.
新的列车代表新的机遇
This new train means new opportunities.
你会需要更多的打手
Gonna need more muscle.
你知道的  我很能打
You know I'm good with my fists.
-那你的朋友呢  -我人脉很广
- And your friend? - I have connections.
也许你还不知道
Oh, maybe you haven't heard.
头等厢不复存在了
There isn't a First Class anymore.
我的人脉不在这列车上
My connections aren't on this train.
他们在我们后面的列车上  谢谢
They're on the one behind us, thanks.
她家人和威尔福德的关系很好
Her family was tight with Wilford.
等他统治这辆列车时  你会希望我在你身边
And when he rules this train, you're gonna want me close.
相信我
Trust me.
但没有那么接近  对吧
But not that close, right, right?
我不需要你们俩带来的麻烦
I don't need the kind of trouble you two bring.
我们会努力做事的
Hey, we'll work for it.
-你想做事吗  -想
- You wanna work? - Yeah.
没事
It's cool.
集市里的化粪池堵住了
Septic's backing up in the market.
我们接受
Yeah, we'll-- we'll take it.
你知道奥德丽在哪吗  谢谢
You know where Audrey is? Thank you.
又开始抽大麻了吗
So there's weed now?
旧习难改
Old habits return.
坐吧
Sit.
为了保住新生活的机会
How far would you go
你愿意付出多少
to protect your chance at a new life?
你是在说你的孩子或安德烈  还是你自己
Are you talking about your baby or Andre or yourself?
我指一切  奥德丽
I'm talking about all of it, Audrey.
但这一切都有风险
But it's all at risk.
你孩子的父亲
The father of your child
要做好对付威尔福德的准备  扎拉
has to prepare for Wilford, Zarah.
他是雪国列车上唯一能获得新生活的机会
He's Snowpiercer's only chance at a new life,
不管你怎么权衡
and whatever you're weighing,
你要竭尽全力保护他
protect him whatever the cost.
该死的  我必须要唱好这首歌
God damn it, I have to get this song right.
我们全都无一幸免  亲爱的
None of our hands are clean, darling.
CW7是一种化合物
CW7's the compound that was shot
用来射入大气层来反射太阳
into the atmosphere to reflect the sun
逆转全球变暖
and reverse global warming.
我记得最后的结果
Yeah, I recall how that ended up.
导致冰川倾泻
Yeah, it cascaded an ice age,
但如果梅的理论没错的话
but if Mel's theory's right,
冰川也许会裂开并倾泻
it might be breaking up and coming down.
这会改变我们所有的气候模式
Which changes every climate model we've ever made.
就是说变暖吗
As in makes it warmer?
因为我们每天都会公布气温  天气还是很冷
'Cause we announce the temperature every day. It is still cold.
在这下面是的  所以我们要往上看
Down here, yeah, which is why we're looking up above.
等等
Wait.
零下71度
Minus 96.
零下65度
Minus 86.
欢迎回来  天才
Welcome back, you beauty.
等等  如果真的开始了  那会需要多久
Wait, if this is really happening, then how long will it take?
我们必须搞清楚  但现在的确是开始了
Well, we have to figure that out, but it's happening.
地球正在恢复生机
The Earth is coming back alive.
莱顿
Layton.
我需要使用威尔福德的补给车厢
I'm gonna need access to Wilford's supply cars--
电池  气象设备  交通工具
batteries, meteorological equipment, transport.
问题是  他绝对不会心甘情愿地
The problem is this-- he's never gonna willingly
参与他无法掌控的任何事
sign up for anything that he's not in charge of.
雪国列车需要一个战斗口号
Snowpiercer needs a rallying cry
不然我们就的在这后面自相残杀
or we're gonna start tearing each other apart back here.
没错  这正是他希望的事
Yeah, and that's exactly what he's hoping for.
所以也许这是我们打败他的方法
Yeah, so maybe this is how we beat him.
-我们的使命是希望  -没错
- The mission is hope. - Yes, it is.
威尔福德  他不只是想要一座城堡
Wilford, he doesn't just want a castle, right?
他想要一个宫廷  他要人尊重他
He wants a court. He needs to be revered.
老伊凡  我在车尾的良师
Old Ivan, my mentor in the tail,
我们经常下国际象棋
we used to play a lot of chess,
他在开局的时候
and he had a defense for an opponent
主动防守对手
with an ego in the opening move--
卡罗-卡恩防御
the Caro-Kann.
国际象棋开局王兵开局的一种
先把棋盘中心让给对手
Give him the center of the board at first.
威尔福德想要击溃希望
Wilford wants to fight hope.
我们逼他也当着他的人面前这么做
We make him do it out in the open in front of his people too.
这很冒险
It's risky.
给他一个舞台  他就会开始做戏
You give him a stage, he'll put on a show.
为了取胜  我们总有一天
We gotta engage with him at some point,
要和他交手
right, for the mission to succeed.
露丝
Ruth.
莱顿  你会需要她的协助
Layton, you need her on your side.
让开  走开
Make way, stand aside.
公报来了
Communiqué coming through.
瞧瞧谁加入了工人阶级
Well, look who's joined the working classes.
露丝  天呐  你好
Ruth, gosh, hi.
奥斯维勒先生正在教我工作是一种商品
Mr. Osweiller is teaching me about how work is a commodity.
我好激动
Please, I'm so excited.
这是给威尔福德先生吗
Is that for Mr. Wilford?
不用你管
Never you mind,
但我们也许会比你想象中更快见到他
but we might be seeing him sooner than you think.
有消息来了  先生
A message, sir.
他们有一个紧急的科学发现要讨论
They have an urgent scientific discovery to discuss.
他们提议在头等厢餐车开会
They're proposing a summit in First Class dining.
绝不能接受
That's a nonstarter.
肯定是和那个样本有关
It has something to do with that sample.
我就知道她没和我说实话
I knew she wasn't being straight with me.
或者是虚张声势  为了引你出去
Or it's a bluff to draw you out.
我的确是会暴露
It's true I'd be exposed,
但话说回来  他们也会暴露
but then again, so would they.
这是一次正式会见  赛克斯
It's an audience, Sykes.
-这是一个机会  -机会
- It's an opening. - An opening?
什么机会  攻击他们的机会吗
To what? To attacking them?
不是他们  是他
Not them. Him.
告诉他们我们接受
Tell them we'll accept.
今晚我们邀请到一位最特别的客人
Tonight we host the most special guest,
我们的创造者
our very creator.
欢迎他的同时  请记住
Now, as we welcome him, remember this.
孔雀羽毛让我们知道这种鸟很强壮
It's the peacock's feathers that tell us the bird is strong.
其他人或许会说是高地和视线
Now, others may speak of high ground and sight lines,
但我们最了解第一道防线
but we know the first line of defense.
是干净利落的衣领  是精美绝伦
It's crisp collars. It's polished perfection.
是正合时宜的续杯
It's well-timed refills.
今晚在所有夜晚中  你们要让我骄傲
Now, tonight of all nights, you go and make me proud.
去吧
Go on then.
我需要跟你谈谈
Hey, I need a minute.
警探  你好像有点焦躁不安
Detective, you seem a little wound up.
被袭击的车尾人  是莱茨
The Tailie who was assaulted, it was Lights.
-她还好吗  -不  -他们弄残了她的手
- Is she okay? - No, they maimed her hand.
多名袭击者  没有目击证人
Multiple assailants, no witnesses.
-看样子是有组织的袭击  -有组织
- It seems like it was organized. - Organized?
她才上任三小时
She's been on the job three hours,
就已经碰上了阴谋
she's already got a conspiracy.
这工作是你给我的  让我来处理
Hey, you gave me the job. Let me do it.
这是你的案子
It's your case.
你的直觉是什么
What's your gut tell you?
我的直觉  好
My gut? Okay.
可能只是车尾偏见
It could be just Tail prejudice,
但有人想要趁我们脆弱时制造混乱
but someone's trying to stir up trouble while we're vulnerable.
要是威尔福德已经到这儿了呢
What if Wilford's already here?
我能加入你吗
Can I join you?
-你还好吗  -我很好
- You good? - I'm fine.
是吗
Yeah?
给我看看
Show me.
算是平局吧
I'm calling it a tie.
我总有一天会赢你
I'm gonna beat you one day.
-你会老去的  -现在不会
- You're gonna age out. - Not this day.
冷淡鲍勃会支持你的  赛克斯也会
Icy Bob will have your back, Sykes too.
我知道
I know.
莱顿只是个小磕绊
Layton's just a blip.
他们晚上入睡时感谢的人是我
It's me they thank when their heads hit the pillow at night.
但是让我下手
But having me do it--
是为了惩罚梅兰妮  对吗
it's just about punishing Melanie, right?
不  我们在讲一个故事  艾莉克斯
No, we're telling a story, Alex.
她从我手中夺走了列车  他又从她手中夺走
She takes the train from me, he takes it from her,
现在你  她的女儿  要弥补这一切
and now you, her own daughter, makes things right.
这是份浓汤
It's a thick soup.
你现在已经超越了她在你这么大时所取得的成就
You have come so much further than her at your age.
我等不及要你去看看前车的样子了
I can't wait for you to see it up there.
会让你震撼不已的
It'll take your breath away.
你会接手
And you'll take the helm.
但是
But...
不会像凯文那样  场面会很乱
It won't be like Kevin. It'll get messy.
你内心的一部分会质疑它
A part of you will question it,
剧痛
the pangs.
你得把它们挡在外面
You have to block them out.
我知道你有多坚强  乔茜
I know how strong you are, Josie.
人们总是寄望你能做正确的事
People always look to you for the right thing to do.
我又找到了一条路  乔茜
I have a path again, Josie.
别把它从我身边夺走
Don't try to take it away from me.
我代表雪国列车  欢迎您上车  先生
On behalf of Snowpiercer, welcome aboard, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
看到你们骄傲地穿着蓝绿色制服真好
It's such a pleasure to see the teal worn with such pride.
我们竭尽全力  先生
We do our best, sir.
抱歉  先生  我得对你搜身
Apologies, sir, I'm gonna have to search you.
当然了  罗切
Of course you do, Roche.
这是自然的
I wouldn't expect anything less.
请把手举起来  谢谢
Arms up please. Thank you.
好了  请往这边走
Okay, this way, please.
威尔福德  威尔福德
Wilford, Wilford!
你好  见到你真高兴
Hello. How lovely to see you.
我喜欢你们对这里所做的改造
I love what you've done with the place.
-太棒了  -正义
- It's absolutely amazing. - Justice!
你好  开心点
Hello. Oh, cheer up.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, darling.
见到你真高兴  见到你真高兴
Good to see you. Good to see you.
It's lovely to see you, lovely to see you.
-威尔福德先生  -让她过来
- Mr. Wilford, Mr. Wilford! - Oh, let her through.
过来  孩子
Come, child.
你为什么看着这么脸熟
Why do you look familiar?
-我是LJ·福爵  -当然了
- I'm LJ Folger. - So you are.
罗伯特和莱拉怎么样
How are Robert and Lilah?
他们在战争中死了
They died in the war.
节哀顺变
Oh, you have my deepest condolences.
好了  好了
Come on, come on.
你在这里还有朋友  先生
You still have friends up here, sir.
闭嘴
Hey, keep your mouth shut.
好了  威尔福德先生  别停下
Okay, Mr. Wilford, let's keep it moving.
-附属列车在等着  -好的
- The subtrain is waiting. - Aye, aye.
你好
Hello there.
你好  你好
Hello there, hi. Hello.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
威尔福德先生
Mr. Wilford.
八个人  谢谢
Table for eight, please.
你好
Hello.
我得承认  你们的关系让我困惑
I will confess, this relationship confuses me.
你不是推翻了她吗
I thought you overthrew her.
我们有过不和
We've had our moments.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我代表雪国列车
on behalf of Snowpiercer,
我想欢迎威尔福德先生和他的组员上车
I would like to welcome Mr. Wilford and his crew aboard.
-没错  威尔福德先生  -谢谢  谢谢
- Yes, we do, Mr. Wilford! - Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢你  莱顿先生
Thank you, Mr. Layton.
我很期待
I look forward to
在我的夜车水族馆头等厢里吃晚餐
the aquarium First Class dining in my Nightcar.
恐怕我们今天要先解决
I'm afraid we have graver concerns
-其他更重要的问题  威尔福德先生  -当然了
- to address today, Mr. Wilford. - Of course.
需要我们作为同一列车上的人
Concerns that must be addressed together
共同解决的问题
as one train.
首席工程师卡维尔
Head Engineer Cavill.
谢谢
Thank you.
大爱丽丝和雪国列车上的各位
People of Snowpiercer and Big Alice...
地球正在变暖
the Earth is warming.
上大气层的CW7正在消失
CW7 in the upper atmosphere is dissipating.
也许用不了1000年
Instead of 1,000-year timeframe,
地球能在我们有生之年
the planet may create warm spots
演变出能让我们重新生存的
that could support recolonization
温暖地带
in our lifetimes.
那么
Now...
我们有很多事要学  有很多准备要做
we have a lot to learn, a lot to prepare for,
我们必须要齐心协力
and we have to do it together.
首先  我们要启动
First, we need to boot up
落基山脉的布雷斯劳尔研究站
the Breslauer Research Station in the Rocky Mountains.
我们就是刚从那条轨道来的  雪国列车开不了
We just traveled that line. It's not fit for Snowpiercer.
绝对没有办法抵达的
She'd never make it through.
第二  我们要向亚洲大陆放出大量
Second, we need to release a network of sounding balloons
探空气球
across the continent into Asia
一直到喜马拉雅终点站
as far as the Himalayan terminus.
这些气球会将数据传递到研究站
The balloons will relay data to the research station,
雪国列车将花一个月时间
and Snowpiercer will return in a month's time
去收集数据
to collect it,
我们这么做是希望可以找到
at which point, we hope to have found
我们想找的东西  也就是在地图上
what we're looking for-- an X on the map
标记出能让生命重新开始的地方
where life can begin again.
我们要怎么相信你这番话
How are we to believe any of this?
这可是一个假冒了我七年的女人
This is the woman who pretended to be me for seven years.
她能编出最离奇的谎言
There's no lie too audacious for her.
她没有撒谎
She's not lying.
这位沾满鲜血的偷渡者来声援她了
Oh, and here is the blood-soaked stowaway to back her up.
你们俩可真般配啊
How comforting for you all.
一个小偷  一个叛乱分子
A thief and a rebel.
-威尔福德先生  -怎么了
- Uh, Mr. Wilford, sir. - Yes?
CW7会...我不是反驳你的意思  先生
The CW7 will-- not to contradict you, sir.
你说吧
Yeah, just say it.
CW7可能被埋在了
The CM7, it may have been buried
-更大的化合物里  -硫酸铵
- in a larger compound. - Ammonium sulfate.
如果我们观测到的浓度是这个...
And if that's what it was in the quantities we saw--
这理论能站住脚  先生
The theory holds, sir.
那你怎么说  威尔福德先生
So what do you say, Mr. Wilford?
我们要不要在地球上再度安营
Should we recolonize Earth or nah?
好吧  要启动研究站
All right, to get the research station online,
-就必须配备人手  -是的
- it'll need to be manned. - That's right.
要派人留在那里一个月
Someone out there for a month.
一个了解研究站  懂科学技术
Someone who knows the station, someone who knows the science,
有大量经验的人
someone with breach experience.
是的
Yes.
你一开始就该说明白这一点的  梅兰妮
You really should have led with that, Melanie.
这人选非你莫属
For this to work, has to be you.
什么
What?
我相信除了我们的首席工程师以外
I'm sure our head engineer isn't the only scientist
-还有其他人能去  -但只有她可以  莱顿先生
- who can man this station. - Oh, but she is, Mr. Layton.
只有她  对吗  梅兰妮
She is, aren't you, Melanie?
是你的聪明才智才让我们走到了这一步
Your brilliance is exactly why we're here.
只不过可惜的是  你的提案
It's just unfortunate that your projects
总是需要丢下某些人
always seem to require leaving someone behind.
终于轮到你了  梅兰妮
Your turn, Melanie.
轮到你了
Your turn.
这是我的条件
Those are my terms.
停止一切对立行为
All hostilities cease.
这是我的条件
Those are my terms.
列车之间必须要合作
The trains have to work together.
我也巴不得呢
I want nothing more.
那我会给你列出所需要的工具清单
Then I'll send an inventory of equipment that I need.
未来...在车外
The future...is outside!
不要动手
No.
让我们一起找到新的伊甸园
Let's go find a new Eden!
并开始和平与合作的新时代
And so begins a new era of peace and cooperation!
一辆由共同目标所结合的列车
One train bound by common cause!
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
很成功
Well, that worked.
他说得没错  该是我去
He's right. It should be me.
你应该先告诉我一声的
Could've let me know.
保护好这辆列车
Just keep the train in one piece, huh?
要回来接我
Come back to get me.
你最好去跟他握个手
You better go shake his hand.
莱茨
Lights.
我要看看你的手
I need you to show me your hand.
拜托  莱茨  我要看看
Please, Lights, I gotta see it.
威尔福德
Wilford!
谢谢
Thank you.
乔茜
Josie.
不许说这都是为了我
Don't you dare say this is for me.
这是为了我们所有人  这是希望
It's for all of us. It's hope.